Guide to the Walter L. Meseck papers, 1967-1995 MS2076
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Walter L. Meseck papers
1967-1995
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Meseck, Walter L.
MS2076
0.5 Linear Feet
Collection contains materials related to the Chesapeake and Ohio (C&O) Canal, primarily after it became a national park in 1971. All materials cover the time span from 1967 to 1995, and all relate directly to the C&O Canal.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Historical or Biographical Note
Walter L. Meseck has hiked and biked the length of the Chesapeake and Ohio (C&O) Canal from Cumberland, MD to Washington, DC, a distance of 184.5 miles. He first biked the canal path in the early 1960s. Meseck hiked the C&O Canal on foot for the first time in 1979 as a member of the C&O Canal Association, a group of volunteers dedicated to preserving the canal, during the Justice William O. Douglas anniversary hike. During the 1984 Justice William O. Douglas anniversary hike, he hiked the portion of the trail from Williamsport, MD to Washington, DC.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains materials related to the Chesapeake and Ohio (C&O) Canal, primarily after it became a national park in 1971. All materials cover the time span from 1967 to 1995, and all relate directly to the C&O Canal.
Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Meseck, Walter L.; Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association
- Letter from Bruce Wood, hike committee chairman, to Walter L. Meseck, 1979 February 07 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Thirteen page document, a collection of day-to-day logs for the Justice Douglas through hike, 1979 April 16-28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Itinerary, Justice Douglas through hike, 1979 April 16-28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Two copies of the flyer, "C&O Canal Association 25th Anniversary Hike", 1979 April 15-28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Two page (on single sheet) hand-written list of participants in Justice Douglas through hike, 1979 April 16-28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- One page paper, "Breakdown of Statistics for C&O Canal Towpath Hike", 1979 April 16-28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Two page paper, "1979 Hike reunion Song" (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Invitation to "C&O Canal Hikers of '79 Reunion Time" by Dale Jackson, with attachment: map with directions, titled "C&O Hikers", 1979 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Papers, "Guide to the Geology and Engineering of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, Seneca to Carderock" by W.E. & G.H. Davies, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publication, "Alexandria Canal, " with insert: flyer, "The Wabash and Erie Canal", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Form, "Reservation for the 1980 Reunion Hike, with attachment: "Along the Towpath", 1980 April (Box 1, Folder 11)
- C&O Canal Association brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letter "To Whom It May Concern" from Walter L. Meseck,including a list of archival items donated to the archives, 1995 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Publication, "C&O Canal National Historical Park Visitor Information", 1978 August (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "The Towline", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Two copies of publication, "A Collection of Maps of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Letter from Walter Meseck to Dave Johnson with attachment: two copies of article "Obligations of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal", 1994 February-April 14 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Article, "'84 Down.. .", by Arnold S. Platou, Hagerstown Herald Mail, 1984 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Article, "An Anniversary Hike Among the Blubells" by paul Hodge, Washington Post, 1979 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Article, "Hike for History" by Jay Votel, as well as "Canal Boat Song" by Sigurd Olsen and Merlo Pusey, and "A Canal Chronology" Hagerstown Herald mail, 1984 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Article, "Canal Hikers Stop At Brunswick" Brunswick Citizen, 1979 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Newspaper photograph with caption, showing Tom Han at MP 1, C&O Canal towpath, 1979 April (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Article, "Hikers Brave Cold Winds On Canal" by Paul Hodge, Washington Post, 1979 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Small format color photo of Walter L. Meseck at MP 0.0, Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Small format color photo of Walter Meseck and Bill and Jan Prutting at MP 0.0., Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Small format color photo of Walter Meseck and Jan Prutting, MP 0.0, Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Four-by-six photo of Walter Meseck on towpath near Key Bridge, Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Four-by-six color photo of Walter L. Meseck on C&O Canal towpath opposite Canal Road in Washington, DC, Justice Douglas through-hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Four-by-six color photo of Walter L. Meseck on the C&O Canal towpath opposite Canal Road in Washington, DC, Justice Douglas through-hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Four-by-six photo of Walter Meseck and Jan Prutting on towpath near Key Bridge, Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Four-by-six color photo of Walter L. Meseck and his niece (Jan Prutting) on the C&O Canal towpath opposite Canal Road in Road in Washington, DC, Justice Douglas through-hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Black-and-white 8x10 photo of Walter Meseck and Emmie Johns (now Woodward) on Potomac River shoreline, Douglas Reunion Hike, 1979 April (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Black-and-white 8x10 photo of hikers at beginning of Douglas Reunion Hike, Cumberland, 1979 April (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Eight color slides, Justice Douglas Reunion Hike, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 34)